Register of the Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman collection, 1899-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
- Isaac Babel File, 1913-2002.
  - Works, 1913-2002.
    - Utwory odnalezione, Warsaw, 1971 (Folder 66: 3)
      (I.80). Polish translation of selected writings
    - Mes premiers honoraires, Paris, 1972 (Folder 66: 4)
      (I.81). French translation of selected writings
    - El libro de bolsillo, 1972 (Folder 66: 5)
      (I.82). Spanish translation of Odesskie rasskazy and other writings
    - Werke, first volume, Berlin, 1973 (Box-folder 67: 1)
      (I.83). German translation of Sobrannoe
    - Werke, second volume, Berlin, 1973 (Folder 67: 2)
      (I.83A)
    - Collected Stories, New York, 1974; See also Box 61, folder 2 (Folder 67: 3-5)
      (I.84, I.84A, I.84B). Reprint of English translation by Walter Morison.
    - "Six Stories," Stand, vol. 15, no. 4, 1974 (Box-folder 68: 1)
      (I.85)
    - El ejercito de caballeria, Moscow, 1974 (Folder 68: 2)
      (I.86). Spanish translation of Konarmiia
    - Die Reiterarmee, Leipzig, 1975 (Folder 68: 3)
      (I.87). German translation of Konarmiia
    - Rudá jízda a jiné prózy, Prague, 1975 (Folder 68: 4)
      (I.88). Czech translation of Rasskazy and Izbrannoe
    - Rasskazy, Letchworth, 1976 (Folder 68: 5)
      (I.89)
    - Mariia, Letchworth, 1976 (Folder 68: 6)
      (I.90)
    - Ratsa Armee, Odessa Lood, Novellid Maria, Tallinn, 1977 (Folder 68: 7)
      (I.91). Estonian translation of Konarmiia, Odesskie rasskazy, and Mariia
    - Zakat, Letchworth, 1977 (Box-folder 69: 1)
      (I.92)
    - Mariia, Letchworth, 1978 (Folder 69: 2)
      (I.93)
    - Forgotten Prose, Ann Arbor, 1978 (Folder 69: 3-5)
      (I.94, I.94A, I.94B). English translation of Zabytyi Babel'
    - Zabytyi Babel', Ann Arbor, 1979. (Folder 69: 6)
    - Detstvo i drugie rasskazy, Jerusalem
      - First edition, 1979 (Folder 69: 7)
        (I.95)
      - Second edition, 1989 (Folder 69: 8)
        (I.95A)
    - Rasskazy, Letchworth (Box 70)
      - First printing, 1980 (Folder 70: 1)
        (I.96)
      - Second printing, 1981 (Folder 70: 2)
        (I.97)
    - Konarmiia, Letchworth, 1981 (Folder 70: 3)
      (I.98)
    - "Marya" in Michael Glenny, ed., The Golden Age of Soviet Theatre, Harmondsworth, 1981 (Folder 70: 4)
      (I.99)
    - Odesskie rasskazy, Chicago, 1982 (Folder 70: 5)
      (I.100)
    - Prosa, Berlin, 1983 (Folder 70: 6)
      (I.101). German translation of Izbrannoe
    - Konarmiia, Ann Arbor, 1983 (Folder 70: 7)
      (I.102)
    - L'armata a cavallo, Milano, 1983 (Folder 70: 8)
      (I.103). Italian translation of Konarmiia
    - Lehimshekh el Ha-Shemesh, Tel Aviv, 1984 (Folder 70: 9)
      (I.104). Hebrew translation of Rasskazy
    - Rudá jízda a jiné prózy, Prague, 1984 (Box-folder 71: 1)
      (I.105). Czech translation of Rasskazy and Izbrannoe
    - You Must Know Everything, New York, 1984 (Folder 71: 2)
      (I.106). English translation of Rasskazy
    - Izbrannoe, Minsk, 1986 (Folder 71: 3)
      (I.107)
    - Konarmiia, Kalmykia, 1986 (Folder 71: 4)
      (I.108)
    - "Lyubka the Cossack," in Bernard Guilbert Guerney, ed., The Portable Russian Reader, New York, 1959 (Folder 71: 5)
      (I.109)
    - Heil Ha-Parashim, Tel Aviv, 1987 (Box-folder 72: 1)
      (I.110). Hebrew translation of Konarmiia i drugie rasskazy
    - Nachalato, Sofia, 1987 (Folder 72: 2)
      (I.111). Bulgarian translation of Izbrannoe
    - Odesskie rasskazy i drugie proizvedeniia, Tel Aviv(?), 1988 (Folder 72: 3)
      (I.112)
    - Peterburg 1918, Ann Arbor, 1989 (Folder 72: 4)
      (I.113)
    - Konarmiia, Alma-Ata, 1989 (Folder 72: 5-6)
      (I.114, I.114A)
    - Probuzhdenie, Tblisi, 1989 (Box-folder 73: 1-2)
      (I.115, I.115A)
    - Konarmiia, Kiev, 1989 (Folder 73: 3)
      (I.116)
    - Konarmiia, Murmansk, 1989 (Folder 73: 4)
      (I.117)
    - Konarmiia, Baku, 1989 (Folder 73: 5)
      (I.118)
    - Rasskazy, Moscow, 1989 (Box-folder 74: 1)
      (I.119)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow, 1990 (Folder 74: 2)
      (I.120)
    - L'armato a cavallo, Venice, 1990 (Folder 74: 3)
      (I.121). Italian translation of Konarmiia
    - Collected Stories, London, 1990; See also Box 61, folder 2 (Folder 74: 4)
      (I.122). Reprint of English translation by Morison.
    - Konarmiia, Odesskie rasskazy, Odessa, 1990 (Folder 74: 5-7)
      (I.123, I.123A)
    - Konarmiia, Odesskie rasskazy, Odessa, 1990 (Box-folder 75: 1)
      (I.123B)
    - Benya Krik, Sakhalin, 1990 (Folder 75: 2)
      (I.124)
    - Izbrannoe, Dushanbe, 1990 (Folder 75: 3)
      (I.125)
    - Sochineniia, Moscow, 1990
      - Volume one (Folder 75: 4)
        (I.126)
      - Volume two (Folder 75: 5)
        (I.126A)
    - Izbrannoe, Frunze (I.127, I.128) (Box-folder 76: 1-2)
    - Kak eto delalos' v Odesse, St. Petersburg, 1991 (Folder 76: 3-4)
      (I.129, I.129A)
    - Konarmiia, Odesskie rasskazy, P'esy, Stat'i, Pis'ma, Irkutsk, 1991 (Box-folder 77: 1)
      (I.130)
    - Likuia i sodrogaias', Odessa, 1992 (Folder 77: 2)
      (I.131)
    - Collected Stories, Chatham, 1993; See also Box 61, folder 2 (Folder 77: 3)
      (I.132). Reprint of English translation by Walter Morison, 1955.
    - Chetyre rasskaza, London, 1993 (Folder 77: 4)
      (I.133)
    - Collected Stories, London, 1994 (Folder 77: 5)
      (I.134). English translation by David McDuff of Konarmiia, Rasskazy, and Odesskie rasskazy
    - L'armata a cavallo, Venice, 1994 (Box-folder 78: 1)
      (I.135). Reprint of Italian translation of Konarmiia
    - Izbrannoe, Moscow, 1996 (Folder 78: 2)
      (I.136)
    - Művei, Budapest, 1986 (Folder 78: 3)
      (I.137). Hungarian translation of Izbrannoe
    - Sochineniia v dvukh tomakh, Moscow, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Volume one (Folder 79: 1)
        (I.138)
      - Volume two (Folder 79: 2)
        (I.139)
    - V Odesse I okolo, Ekaterinburg, 2001 (Folder 79: 3)
      (I.140)
    - Sobranie sochineniia v dvukh tomakh, Moscow, 2002
      - Volume one (Folder 79: 4)
        (I.141)
      - Volume two (Box-folder 80: 1)
        (I.141A)
    - Collected Stories, New York, 2002 (Folder 80: 2)
      (I.142). English translation by Peter Constantine of Konarmiia, Rasskazy, and Odesskie rasskazy
    - Collected Works of Isaac Babel, New York, 2002 (Folder 80: 3)
      (I.143). English translation by Peter Constantine of Sobranie
    - Konarmiia, Rasskazy, P'esy, St. Petersburg, 1998 (Box-folder 81: 1)
      (no number assigned)
  - Anthologies, 1929-2000.
    Printed copies of volumes containing selections by Babel, with the titles of his writings being listed first
    - "The Letter," in Joshua Kuntiz, ed., Azure Cities, New York, 1929 (Folder 81: 2)
      (II.1)
    - "The Letter," "Salt," and "The Death of Dolgushov," in John Cournos, ed., Short Stories out of Soviet Russia, New York, 1929 (Folder 81: 3)
      (II.2)
    - "Gedali" and "Dolgushov's Death," in S. Konovalov, ed., Bonfire: Stories out of Soviet Russia, London, 1932 (Box-folder 82: 1)
      (II.3)
    - "The End of Saint Ipaty" and "The Awakening," in George Reavey and Marc Slonim, eds., Soviet Literature: An Anthology, London, 1933 (Folder 82: 2)
      (II.4)
    - "A Letter," in Modern Russian Classics, Boston, 1936 (Folder 82: 3)
      (II.5)
    - "The Birth of a King," in Elisaveta Fen, ed., Modern Russian Stories, London, 1943 (Folder 82: 4)
      (II.6)
    - "In the Cellar" and "Karl-Yankel," in John Rodker, ed., Soviet Anthology, London, 1943 (Folder 82: 5)
      (II.7)
    - "The King," in Janko Lavrin, Russian Humorous Stories, London, 1946 (Box-folder 83: 1)
      (II.8)
    - "The Letter," in Joshua Kunitz, ed., Russian Literature since the Revolution, New York, 1948 (Folder 83: 2)
      (II.9)
    - "The King," in Bernard Guilbert Guerney, ed., New Russian Stories, Norfolk, 1953 (Folder 83: 3)
      (II.10)
    - "Liubka the Cossack," in Bernard Guilbert Guerney, ed., The Portable Russian Reader, New York, 1947 (Folder 83: 4)
      (II.12)
    - "In the Basement," in George Reavey, ed., 14 Great Short Stories by Soviet Authors, New York, 1959 (Box 84)
      - U.S. printing (Folder 84: 1)
        (II.13)
      - Canadian printing (Folder 84: 2)
        (II.14)
    - "Aphonka" and "The Awakening," in Bernard Guilbert Guerney, ed., An Anthology of Soviet Literature in the Soviet Period from Gorki to Pasternak, New York, 1960 (Folder 84: 3)
      (II.15)
    - "An Unorthodox Cavalry Maneuvre" and "My First Goose," in Ronald Hingley, ed., Modern Russian Reader, New York, 1960 (Folder 84: 4)
      (II.16)
    - "The King" and "A Letter," in F. D. Reeve, ed., Great Soviet Short Stories, New York, 1962 (Folder 84: 5)
      (II.17)
    - "First Love," in Gerda Charles, ed., Modern Jewish Stories, London, 1963 (Box-folder 85: 1)
      (II.18)
    - "The Journey," in Patricia Blake and Max Hayward, eds., Dissonant Voices in Soviet Literature, New York, 1962 (Folder 85: 2)
      (II.19)
    - "The Rabbi's Son," in Joseph Leftwich, ed., Yisröel: The First Jewish Omnibus, New York, 1963 (Folder 85: 3)
      (II.20)
    - "How Things Were Done in Odessa," in Maurice Friedberg and Robert A. Maguire, eds., A Bilingual Collection of Russian Short Stories, volume two, New York, 1965 (Box-folder 86: 1)
      (II.21)
    - "First Love," in Norman Podhoretz, ed., The Commentary Reader, New York, 1966 (Folder 86: 2)
      (II.22)
    - "In Odessa" and "The Awakening," in Nathan Ausubel, ed., A Treasury of Jewish Humor, New York, 1967 (Box-folder 87: 1)
      (II.23)
    - "Di Grasso: A Tale of Odessa," in Lionel Trilling, ed., The Experience of Literature, Garden City, 1967 (Folder 87: 2)
      (II.24)
    - "The Death of Dolgushov," in R. G. Davis-Poynter, ed., For Freedom: Theirs and Ours, London, 1968 (Folder 87: 3)
      (II.25)
    - "Sunset," in Peter Reddaway, ed., Soviet Short Stories, volume two, London, 1968 (Box-folder 88: 1)
      (II.26)
    - "The Death of Dogushov," in C. G. Bearne, ed., Modern Russian Short Stories 2, London, 1969 (Folder 88: 2)
      (II.27)
    - "Line and Colour," London Magazine, no. 100, 1969 July/August (Folder 88: 3)
      (II.28)
    - "Inspiration," in Judith Burnley, ed., Penguin Modern Stories 4, Harmondsworth, 1969 (Folder 88: 4)
      (II.29)
    - "The Story of My Dovecote" and "The Widow," in Krystyna Pomorska, ed., Fifty Years of Russian Prose, volume one, Cambridge, Mass., 1971 (Folder 88: 5)
      (II.30)
    - "Istoriia moei golubiatni," in Venedikt Milchev and Ivan Tsvetkov, eds., Goluboe i zelenoe, Moscow, 1971 (Box-folder 89: 1)
      (II.31)
    - "Probuzhdenie," in S. I. Timina, ed., Russkaia sovetskaia proza, Moscow, 1978 (Folder 89: 2)
      (II.32)
    - "Sundown," in Laurence Senelick, ed., Russian Satiric Comedy, New York, 1983 (Folder 89: 3)
      (II.33). English translation of Zakat
    - "Argamak," "Izmena," "Sol'," and "Smert' Dolgushova," in N. L. Koshaleva, ed., Oktiabr'skii vikhr', Magadan, 1977 (Folder 89: 4)
      (II.34)
    - "Ty promorgal, kapitan!," in D. G. Terent'evaia, ed., Zhivaia voda, Moscow, 1981 (Folder 89: 5)
      (II.35)
    - "Sol'," in S. Borovikov, ed., Antologiia russkogo sovetskogo rasskaza, Moscow, 1985 (Box-folder 90: 1)
      (II.36)
    - "Oil," in Galina Bazhanova, ed., Anthology of Russian Short Stories, volumes one and two, Moscow, 1985 (Folder 90: 2)
      (II.37)
    - "In the Rest Home," "Without a Homeland," "My First Goose," and "Diary: 1920," in Carl R. Proffer, Ellendea Proffer, Ronald Meyer, and Mary Ann Szporluk, eds., Russian Literature of the Twenties: An Anthology, Ann Arbor, 1987 (Folder 90: 3)
      (II.38)
    - "The King" and "A Letter," in F. D. Reeve, ed., Great Soviet Short Stories, New York, 1990 (Box-folder 91: 1)
      (II.39). Reprint of 1962 edition
    - "My First Goose," "How It Was Done in Odessa," and "My First Fee," in Clarence Brown, ed., The Portable Twentieth-Century Russian Reader, New York, 1993 (Folder 91: 2)
      (II.40)
    - "And Then They Were None" and "The Rabbi's Son," in David G. Roskies, ed., The Literature of Destruction: Jewish Responses to Catastrophe, Philadelphia, 1988 (Folder 91: 3)
      (II.41)
    - "The Death of Dolgushov," in Gleb Struve, ed., Russian Stories, New York, 1990 (Box-folder 92: 1)
      (II.42)
    - "Korol'," "Kak eto delalos' v Odesse," "Otets," "Liubka kazak," and "Froim Grach," in O. V. Filimonova, ed., Odesskaia pleiada, Kiev, 1990 (Folder 92: 2)
      (II.43)
    - "Guy de Maupassant," in Ron Hansen and Jim Shephard, eds., You've Got to Read This, 1994 (Folder 92: 3)
      (II.44)
    - "Shabbas Nachamu," in William Novak and Moshe Waldoks, eds., The Big Book of Jewish Humor, New York, 1994 (Folder 92: 4)
      (II.45)
    - "The Story of My Dovecote," in Ellen Frankel, The Jewish Spirit, New York, 1997 (Box-folder 93: 1)
      (II.46)
    - Ilana Hammerman, ed., Mehuva leshisha sofrim shel' hameah haesrim, Tel Aviv, 2000 (Folder 93: 2)
      (II.47). Includes Hebrew translations of "Moi pervyi gus'" and "Moi pervyi gonorar"
  - Criticism, 1924-2000.
    Printed copies of monographs and serial issues, which refer in part or in whole to Babel
    - Lef, no. 2 (6), 1924 (Folder 93: 3)
      (III.1)
    - Mirsky, D. S., Prince, Contemporary Russian Literature, New York, 1926 (Folder 93: 4)
      (III.2)
    - B. V. Kazanskogo and Iu. N. Tynianova, eds., I. E. Babel'
      - 1928 edition, Leningrad (Folder 93: 5)
        (III.3)
      - 1973 edition, Letchworth (Folder 93: 6)
        (III.4)
    - Polonskii, Viacheslav, O sovremennoi literature
      - 1928 edition, Moscow (Folder 93: 7)
        (III.5)
      - 1929 edition, Moscow/Leningrad (Box-folder 94: 1)
        (III.6)
    - Freeman, Joseph, et al., Voices of October, New York, 1930 (Folder 94: 2)
      (III.7)
    - Eastman, Max, Artists in Uniform: A Study of Literature and Bureaucratism, New York, 1934 (Folder 94: 3)
      (III.8)
    - Struve, Gleb, Soviet Russian Literature, London, 1935 (Folder 94: 4)
      (III.9)
    - Tkhorzhevskii, Ivan, Russaia literatura, Paris, 1950 (Box-folder 95: 1)
      (III.10)
    - Ernest J. Simmons, ed., Through the Glass of Soviet Literature, New York, 1953 (Folder 95: 2)
      (III.11)
    - Matthewson, Rufus W., Jr., The Positive Hero in Russian Literature, New York, 1958 (Folder 95: 3)
      (III.12)
    - Zavalishin, Vyacheslav, Early Soviet Writers, New York, 1958 (Folder 95: 4)
      (III.13)
    - Van der Eng-Liedmeier, A. M., Soviet Literary Characters, The Hague, 1959 (Box-folder 96: 1)
      (III.14)
    - Mosty, no. 9, 1962 (Folder 96: 2)
      (III.15)
    - Swayze, Harold, Political Control of Literature in the USSR, 1946-1959, Cambridge, Mass., 1962 (Folder 96: 3)
      (III.16)
    - Erhard, Marcelle, Russian Literature, New York, 1963 (Folder 96: 4)
      (III.17)
    - Alexandrova, Vera, A History of Soviet Literature, Garden City, 1963 (Folder 96: 5)
      (III.18)
    - Max Hayward and Leopold Labedz, eds., Literature and Revolution in Soviet Russia, 1917-1962 London, 1963 (Box-folder 97: 1)
      (III.19)
    - Isaak Emmanuilovich Babel', Chicago, n.d. (Folder 97: 2)
      Reprint of Russian edition of 1964 (III.20)
    - Slonim, Marc, Soviet Russian Literature: Writers and Problems, New York
      - 1964 edition (Folder 97: 3)
        (III.21)
      - 1967 edition (Folder 97: 4)
        (III.22)
    - Munblit, Georgii N., Rasskazy o pisateliakh, Moscow, 1968 (Folder 97: 5)
      (III.23)
    - Maguire, Robert A., Red Virgin Soil: Soviet Literature in the 1920's, 1968 (Box-folder 98: 1)
      (III.24)
    - Gasiorowska, Xenia, Women in Soviet Fiction, 1917-1964, Madison, Wisc., 1968 (Folder 98: 2)
      (III.25)
    - Rühle, Jürgen, Literature and Revolution, London, 1969 (Folder 98: 3)
      (III.26)
    - Yarmolinsky, Avrahm, The Russian Literary Imagination, New York, 1969 (Box-folder 99: 1)
      (III.27)
    - Zelinsky, Kornely, Soviet Literature: Problems and People, Moscow, 1970 (Folder 99: 2)
      (III.28)
    - Billington, James H., The Icon and the Axe: An Interpretative History of Russian Culture, New York, 1970 (Folder 99: 3)
      (III.29)
    - Muchnic, Helen, Russian Writers: Notes and Essays, New York, 1971 (Folder 99: 4)
      (III.30)
    - Struve, Gleb, Russian Literature under Lenin and Stalin, Norman, Oklahoma, 1971 (Box-folder 100: 1)
      (III.31)
    - Vasa D. Mihailovich, ed., Modern Slavic Literatures: A Library of Literary Criticism, volume one, New York, 1972 (Folder 100: 2)
      (III.32)
    - Levin, F. I. Babel', Moscow, 1972 (Folder 100: 3)
      (III.33)
    - Carden, Patricia, The Art of Isaac Babel, Ithaca, N. Y., 1972 (Folder 100: 4)
      (III.34)
    - Hallett, Richard W., Isaac Babel, Letchworth, 1972 (Box-folder 101: 1)
      (III.35)
    - Holthusan, Johannes, Twentieth-Century Russian Literature, New York, 1972 (Folder 101: 2)
      (III.36)
    - Halltett, Richard W., Isaac Babel, New York, 1973 (Folder 101: 3)
      (III.37)
    - Brown, Edward J., Russian Literature since the Revolution, New York, 1973 (Folder 101: 4)
      (III.38)
    - Falen, James E., Isaac Babel: Russian Master of the Short Story, Knoxville, Tenn., 1974 (Folder 101: 5)
      (III.39)
    - Moore, Harry T. and Albert Parry, Twentieth-Century Russian Literature, Carbondale, Ill., 1974 (Box-folder 102: 1)
      (III.40)
    - Erlich, Victor, ed., Twentieth-Century Russian Literary Criticism, New Haven, Conn., 1975 (Folder 102: 2)
      (III.41)
    - Auty, Robert and Dimitry Obolensky, An Introduction to Russian Language and Literature, Cambridge, England (III.42) (Folder 102: 3)
    - Markish, Simon, "The Example of Isaac Babel," Commentary, 1977 November (Folder 102: 4)
      (III.43)
    - Lindstrom, Thaïs S., A Concise History of Russian Literature, volume two, New York, 1978 (Folder 102: 5)
      (III.44)
    - Lvov-Rogachevsky, A History of Russian Jewish Literature, Ann Arbor, 1979 (Box-folder 103: 1)
      (III.45)
    - Hingley, Ronald, Russian Writers and Soviet Society, 1917-1978, New York, 1979 (Folder 103: 2)
      (III.46)
    - Svirski, Grigori, A History of Post-War Soviet Writing: The Literature of Moral Opposition, Ann Arbor, 1981 (Folder 103: 3)
      (III.47)
    - Stableford, Tom, The Literary Appreciation of Russian Writers, Cambridge, England, 1981 (Folder 103: 4)
      (III.48)
    - Voronskii, Aleksandr K., Izbrannye stat'i o literature, Moscow, 1982 (Box-folder 104: 1)
      (III.49)
    - Luplow, Carol, Isaac Babel's Red Cavalry, Ann Arbor, 1982 (Folder 104: 2)
      (III.50)
    - Mendelson, Danuta, Metaphor in Babel's Short Stories, Ann Arbor, 1982 (Folder 104: 3)
      (III.51)
    - Yudkin, Leon Israel, Jewish Writing and Identity in the Twentieth Century, New York, 1982 (Folder 104: 4)
      (III.52)
    - Hayward, Max, Writers in Russia, 1917-1978, San Diego, 1983 (Folder 104: 5)
      (III.53)
    - Avins, Carol, Border Crossings: The West and Russian Identity in Soviet Literature, 1917-1934, Berkeley and Los Angeles, 1983 (Box-folder 105: 1)
      (III.54)
    - Lvov, Arkady, "Babel the Jew," Commentary, 1983 March (Folder 105: 2)
      (III.55)
    - Sicher, Efraim, Style and Structure in the Prose of Isaak Babel', Columbus, Ohio, 1986 (Folder 105: 3)
      (III.56)
    - Ehre, Milton, Isaac Babel, Boston, 1986 (Folder 105: 4)
      (III.57)
    - P. S. Vykhodtsev, ed., Istoriia russkoi sovetskoi literatury, Moscow, 1986 (Folder 105: 5)
      (III.58)
    - Allon, Dafna, "Reflections on the Art of Lying," Commentary, 1986 June (Folder 105: 6)
      (III.59)
    - Bar-Yosef, Hamutal, "On Isaac Babel's 'The Story of My Dovecot'," Prooftexts, vol. 6, no. 3, 1986 September (Box-folder 106: 1)
      (III.60)
    - Apple, Max, "History and Case History in 'Red Calvary' and 'The Day of the Locust'," in Harold Bloom, ed., Nathaniel West, New York, 1986 (Folder 106: 2)
      (III.61)
    - Harold Bloom, ed., Isaac Babel, 1987 (Folder 106: 3)
      (III.62)
    - Polonskii, Viacheslav, O literature, Moscow, 1988 (Folder 106: 4)
      (III.63)
    - Sicher, Efraim, "The 'Jewish Cossack'," Studies in Contemporary Jewry, vol. 4, 1988 (Folder 106: 5)
      (III.64)
    - Gifford, Harry, "Isaac Babel," Grand Street, 1989 Autumn (Folder 106: 6)
      (III.65)
    - Howe, Irving, Selected Writings, 1950-1990, San Diego (Box-folder 107: 1)
      (III.66)
    - Nakhimovsky, Alice Stone, Russian-Jewish Literature and Identity, Baltimore, 1992 (Folder 107: 2)
      (III.67)
    - Belaia, Galina A., et al., 'Konarmiia' Isaaka Babelia, Moscow, 1993 (Folder 107: 3)
      (III.68)
    - Andruszko, Czesław, Zhizneopisanie Babelia Isaaka Emmanuilovicha, Poznan, 1993 (Folder 107: 4)
      (III.69)
    - Erlich, Victor, Modernism and Revolution: Russian Literature in Transition, Cambridge, Mass., 1994 (Folder 107: 5)
      (III.70)
    - Markish, Simon, "The Example of Isaac Babel," in Hana Wirth-Nesher, ed., What is Jewish Literature?, Philadelphia, 1994 (Folder 107: 6)
      (III.71)
    - Zholkovskii, A. K. and M. B. Iampol'skii, Babel'/Babel, Moscow, 1994 (Box-folder 108: 1)
      (III.72)
    - Canadian Slavonic Papers, vol. 36, nos. 1-2, 1994 March-June (Folder 108: 2)
      (III.73). Special number devoted to Babel centenary
    - Mann, Robert, The Dionysian Art of Isaac Babel, Oakland, 1994 (Folder 108: 3)
      (III.74)
    - Sicher, Efraim, Jews in Russian Literature after the Russian Revolution, Cambridge, England, 1995 (Folder 108: 4)
      (III.75)
    - Literaturnoe obozrenie, no. 1, 1995. (Folder 108: 5)
      Includes selection of articles on Babel (III.76)
    - Alter, Robert, "The Jewish Voice," Commentary, 1995 October (Folder 108: 6)
      (III.77)
    - Ozick, Cynthia, "The Year of Writing Dangerously," The New Republic, 1995 May 8 (Folder 108: 7)
      (III.78)
    - Ozick, Cynthia, Fame and Folly: Essays, New York, 1996 (Box-folder 109: 1)
      (III.79)
    - Liberman, Ia. L., Isaak Babel' glazami evreia, Ekaterinburg, 1996 (Folder 109: 2)
      (III.80)
    - Zholokovskii, A. K., "Roman s gonorarom," Literaturnoe obrozrenie, no. 4, 1997 (Folder 109: 3)
      (III.81)
    - Markish, Shimon, Babel' i drugie, Moscow, 1997 (Folder 109: 4)
      (III.82)
    - Paley, Grace, Just as I Thought, New York, 1998 (Folder 109: 5)
      (III.83)
    - Wisse, Ruth R., The Modern Jewish Canon, New York, 2000 (Folder 109: 6)
      (III.84)
    - The Great American Bathroom Book, volume three, Salt Lake City, 1994 (Box-folder 110: 1)
      (III.85)
  - Reference, 1926-1998.
    Printed copies of monographs and serial issues, which refer in part or in whole to Babel. Exceptions are noted
    - Bol'shaia sovetskaia entsiklopediia, volume four, Moscow, 1926 (IV.1). (Folder 110: 2)
      Includes an entry on Babel
    - Literaturnaia entsiklopediia, volume one, Moscow, 1926 (Folder 110: 3)
      (IV.2).
    - Grierson, Philip, Books on Soviet Russia, 1917-1942, London, 1943 (Box-folder 111: 1)
      (IV.3)
    - Ettlinger, Amrei and Joan M. Gladstone, Russian Literature, Theatre, and Art, London, 1946 (Folder 111: 2)
      (IV.4)
    - Reavey, George, Soviet Literature Today, New Haven, 1947 (Folder 111: 3)
      (IV.5).
      Does not refer to Babel
    - Harkins, William E., Dictionary of Russian Literature, New York, 1956. (Folder 111: 4)
      Includes an entry on Babel (IV.6)
    - Literaturnoe nasledstvo iz tvorcheskogo naslediia sovetskikh pisatelei, volume seventy-four, Moscow, 1965 (Box-folder 112: 1)
      (IV.7)
    - Istoriia russkoi sovetskoi literatury, volume 1, Moscow, 1967 (Folder 112: 2)
      (IV.8)
    - Gibian, George, Soviet Russian Literature in English: A Checklist Bibliography, Ithaca, N.Y., 1967 (Folder 112: 3)
      (IV.9)
    - Ocherki istorii russkoi sovetskoi zhurnalistiki, 1933-1945, Moscow, 1968 (Folder 112: 4)
      (IV.10)
    - Proizvedeniia sovetskikh pisatelei v perevodakh na inostrannye iazyki, 1958-1964, Moscow, 1966 (Box-folder 113: 1)
      (IV.11)